Cordula Hansen

VR Developer and UX Designer

About

Artist and design researcher turned VR developer and UX designer specialising in well-crafted VR content.

Contact

Dublin, Ireland +353 87 2815408 cordula@cordhan.net cordhan.net

Skills

Design Research Skills

Ethnography
User interviews
Usability and preference testing
Heuristic analysis
Personas
Storyboarding
User flows
VR information architecture
Rapid prototyping
Client presentations

Tools

Unity 3D HTML5 C# CSS3 JavaScript Adobe Photoshop, Illustrator, XD Balsamiq InVision

Project Management

Agile project management Scrum Kanban VR Collaboration

Communication Skills

Writing for publication Proposal and grant writing Video editing Facilitating workshops and meetings Fluent in English and German

Experience

Self-employed (Dublin, Ireland) VR Designer and Developer

2019-present

Working as VR designer and developer specialising in immersive media, such as VR, AR, XR and experiential spatial design.

Facilitates virtual reality demos, instruction and events for corporate clients. Prepares business analysis for immersive brand experiences. Conducts heuristic analysis and user research for immersive projects. Creates storyboards, 3D prototypes and complete XR experiences (portfolio).

Waterford Institute of Technology (Waterford, Ireland) Director and Principal Investigator

2016-2018

Founded and managed WIT Research Group for Design and Social Innovation (DASI) to facilitate interdisciplinary collaboration and prevent working in silos.

Won funding for a PhD scholar to be recruited for a four-year research project.

Research Supervisor and Lecturer in Design

2005-2018

Designed and delivered student-centric educational programmes from undergraduate to postgraduate level. Managed course content and weekly lectures on graphic design, research methods and business modules.

Organised and facilitated UX design summer schools for graduates, researchers, colleagues and industry collaborators to increase awareness about tech-relevant design paradigms and to integrate industry-relevant content into coursework, increasing students' employment prospects.

Education

VR High-Immersion Nanodegree (2019-)

Udacity

VR Design, Advanced Unity 3D, Performance and Publishing

Certificate in UX Design with Front-End Specialization (2019)

CareerFoundry

Intensive training programme for UX Designers, specializing in UX process and methodology that includes user research, user journeys, user personas, testing, information architecture and visual design fundamentals. Designed real world projects using InVision and Adobe XD.

PhD in Art and Archaeology (2008)

Waterford Institute of Technology

"The Role of the Art Practitioner in Theoretical Archaeology".
Published in peer-reviewed journals and presented at international conferences.

BA(Hons) in Visual Art (2003)

Waterford Institute of Technology

Specialisations in sculpture, multimedia installation and arts management.

VR projects

Emotional Data in a Smart City - VR environment (2018)

Commissioned by Building City Dashboards Research Group, Maynooth University. Funded by Science Foundation Ireland (SFI).

PalmHouse Philosophy - VR artwork (2016-2018)

Virtual Reality Artwork Demo using Google Tiltbrush, exhibited at 404 tech meetup, Autodesk and Google Developer Group Hackathons in Dublin.